right someone came on my live YouTube
stream in fact two people came on my
life YouTube stream it just threw me off
so now I'm gonna record five minutes the
equivalent of live I'm just gonna give
myself one take and then post it so that
the YouTube channel is not live videos
if you want to watch me on live and
comment live and please go to periscope
at cryo democracy I'm on there quite
often live and if you want to get the
updates on YouTube I'll be posting daily
still for my 90 day challenge and
concentrating right now and what's
happening in 2028 when we've been
creating the technology cooperative for
a decade together what is possible and
what we created by 2028 in the parallel
timeline where we started this in 2018
and were able to create it will happen
within a decade of eliminating poverty
and having global world peace so today's
topic is the food system and what the
food system looks like in 2028 and it's
amazing but also hard to explain like
imagine explaining the food system today
to your grandmother as a child like it's
very complex and like right we packaged
food and this happens and Amazon can
deliver it and so I'm gonna talk about
like that in 2028 there are if you live
in an in a city there are a plethora of
systems to opt into so based on your
diet choices based on what you want to
contribute to the group how many hours
you want to spend on your food is how
gourmet the food is is how much human
involvement was required to grow the
food so there are people like Steve for
instance who in 2028 is a slow food
movement person and wants and is working
with a tiny group of 12 other people
they live on the land they spend tons of
time growing their own food biodynamic
way and harvesting it and cooking it
together I mean each individual spends
on average 30 hours a week creating
their food that's definitely not for
everybody there's then Mary and she
likes she has a busy life in the
city and she wants to be able to get her
food as efficiently as possible so she
opts into the Syst the citywide system
that's that feeds a hundred thousand
people and so she only has to contribute
four hours a week and seventy dollars
and she gets all the food prepared for
her that is that is very automated its
automated so that there is less human
time and it's also like there's three
options to choose from a day and you
pick it for the month in it delivers it
to you that day and you are inputting
your share of the labor costs there are
community tools for people who live in
areas that aren't big cities or our big
cities but are in location three
counties that grow food so in Canada we
have a lot of northern communities that
have really astronomical food like their
food costs are really high in 2019 so
they are able to say okay we created
this whole system by asking very simple
questions like what are you currently
doing for food helping people track that
and then offering them the tools to come
together and create solutions together
so northern communities were able to
create their own greenhouses using and
solar-powered indoor growing 3d growing
so that they could have fresh prudent
produce all year round it didn't quite
make sense to have far means they'd
still be astronomical prices for milk or
they brought milk under their diet that
there's they don't have problem freezing
their food so they were able to have
meat available but milk was a little a
little weird to freeze powdered milk and
such there's places different solutions
work in different places so to be able
to to assess that and say what works
best in your northern community and not
this is what's gonna work and you have
to use it giving them the tools to
decide together and then offering them
funding and offering them ways that they
can implement it right away
same with every village around the world
to be able to say what's gonna work for
you to feed your village how can you
come together as a village so that you
all don't have to individually solve
your own problems by figure out how
you're gonna buy rice for that day for
your family and then cook it over your
own stovetop find your own charcoal find
your own if you can come together and
and cook one big pot of rice then you're
already saving time money resources just
doing that then the money in tiniest
you can add more writing to your diet
you can find out like are you growing
your own food how can we help you do
that how can we automate that and so by
offering the tools to collaborate on a
massive scale we just like unleashed
innovation so anyone who comes up with
any solution anywhere in the world it's
that available to everybody and it
doesn't mean it's one-size-fits-all food
is definitely not one-size-fits-all
culturally preference wise dietary
restrictions but now that we have all of
this ability like you get to choose
there's people who eat somewhere
different with a different food club
every day of the week because they eat
with their high school friends on this
day and they're their partners family on
this day unless you can design your life
around food to bring in communities
you're eating with the same community
every night or even with different
people or you have food delivered
because you're not eating with community
at all and you just want to like sit and
decompress you want to eat by yourself
or you it's all available to you
very organized and it's the most
efficient possible we have our own where
there is processed food we've created it
ourselves because we've looked at the
threshold of like right it's making
sense for every single person to create
their own pasta sauce that's a lot of
work creating pasta sauce a lot of work
and we can do it on a massive scale so
at what point does it make sense to bulk
create our pasta sauce and at that
threshold we created pasta sauce company
and we sell it at cost of the labor of
the resources available to our entire
community and where it makes sense to
not have one pasta sauce come factory
giving it globally we have it it's like
rights there's one for your area and one
for your area so we're not having to do
the shipping because we also have access
to that information the shipping
information that what food has grown
where and how much and as we're able to
create the tools to be able to automate
all of that and be able to have access
that information both for everyone to
have access that information so it's
accessible but also so experts have
access and information people who
wouldn't know how to make it more
efficient have access that information
they're not working against the system
so that's a bit of how our food system
works in 2028 I don't yet know what I'm
gonna do tomorrow is video on but I am
going to be doing them this way so
coming on and doing a five ish minutes
one not live but in one take and then
posting it on YouTube
have any questions about the food system
in 2028 put them down below and I will
respond if you have any questions you
would like me to talk about what happens
in 2028 after we've created the global
cooperative tech company together
ask them and I will do an entire video
on that system there's gonna be a
clothing video and a science video in a
health video if there is something that
I you weren't covered sooner rather than
later please let me know in the comments
below and please like and subscribe
because we are going to change the world
together